[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Thus far we've talked about precision, recall, optimism, pessimism.
حتى الآن تحدثنا عن الدقة والإرجاع وعن التفاؤل والتشاؤم.
All sorts of different aspects.
كل أنواع الجوانب المختلفة.
But one of the most surprising things about this whole story is that it's quite
لكن واحدة من أكثر الأشياء إثارة للدهشة حول هذه القصة كلها
easy to navigate from a low precision model to a high precision model from
هي السهولة البالغة في التنقل من نموذج منخفض الدقة إلى نموذج عالي الدقة
a high recall model to a low recall model, so kind of investigate that spectrum.
ومن نموذج إرجاع مرتفع إلى نموذج إرجاع منخفض، أو بمعنى آخر استكشاف تلك المنطقة.
So we can have a low precision, high recall model that's very optimistic,
لذا يمكننا أن نحصل على نموذج دقة منخفضة وإرجاع مرتفع، يحمل الكثير من التفاؤل،
you can have a high precision, low recall model that's very pessimistic, and
كما يمكننا الحصول على نموذج دقة عالية وإرجاع منخفض، يحمل الكثير من التشاؤم،
then it turns out that it's easy to find a path in between.
ليتضح بعد ذلك أنه من السهل العثور على مسار بينهما.
And the question is, how do we do that?
والسؤال هو، كيف نفعل ذلك؟
If you recall from earlier in this course, we assign not just a label,
إذا كنت تتذكر من هذه الدورة في وقت سابق، نحن لا نخصص فقط
+1 or -1, for every data point, but a probability number, let's say, 0.99 or
1+ أو 1، لكل نقطة بيانات، ولكن رقم احتمالية، مثلاً 0.99
being positive for the sushi and everything else were awesome.
أو بالعودة إلى المثال، الإيجابية المتعلقة بالسوشي وكل شيء آخر كان رائعا.
To say 0.55 of being positive for the sushi was good, the service was okay.
افتراض الإيجابية بنسبة 0.55 للسوشي يعطي الانطباع بأنها كانت جيدة، كما كانت الخدمة جيدة.
This probability is I, as I mentioned earlier in the course,
تلك الاحتمالات، كما ذكرت سابقاً في الدورة،
that they are going to be fundamentally useful.
ستكون مفيدة بشكل أساسي.
Now you're going to see a place where they are amazingly useful.
الآن سترى المواضع حيث تكون مفيدة جدًا.
So the probabilities can be used to tradeoff precision with recall.
يمكن استخدام الاحتمالات لمقايضة الدقة بالإرجاع.
And so let's figure that out.
دعونا نفهم ذلك.
So earlier in the course, we just had a fixed threshold to decide if an input
في وقت سابق من الدورة التدريبية، كان لدينا حد ثابت
sentence, x-i, was going to be positive or negative.
لتحديد ما إذا كانت جملة الإدخال، x-i، ستكون إيجابية أم سلبية.
We said, it's going to be positive if the probability is greater than 0.5, and
قلنا، سيكون الأمر إيجابيًا إذا كانت الاحتمالية أكبر من 0.5،
is going to be negative if the probability is less than 0.5,
وسيكون سلبيًا إذا كان الاحتمال أقل من 0.5،
or less than or equal to it.
أو أقل منه أو يساويه.
Now, how can we create an optimistic and
الآن، كيف يمكننا إنشاء نموذج يحمل التفاؤل
pessimistic model by just changing the 0.5 threshold?
وآخر يحمل التشاؤم من مجرد تغيير حد 0.5؟
Let's explore that idea.
لنستكشف هذه الفكرة.
Think about what would happen if we set the threshold,
فكر فيما يمكن أن يحدث إذا قمنا بتعيين الحد الأدنى
instead of being 0.5 to being 0.999.
إلى 0.999 بدلاً من 0.5.
So a data point is only +1 if its probability is greater than 0.999.
لذا، تكون نقطة البيانات 1+ فقط إذا كان احتمالها أكبر من 0.999.
Well, here's what happen.
حسنًا، إليكم ما حدث.
Very few data points would satisfy this.
عدد قليل جدا من نقاط البيانات تفي بذلك.
So if very few data points satisfy this, then very few data points will be +1.
لذلك، إذا كانت نقاط البيانات القليلة جدًا تفي بذلك، فستكون نقاط البيانات ذات القيمة +1 قليلة جدًا.
And the vast majority will be labeled as -1.
وستكون قيمة الأغلبية الساحقة -1.
And we call this classifier the pessimistic classifier.
ونسمي هذا المصنف بالمصنف المتشائم.
Now alternatively, if we change the threshold to be 0.001, then that means
الآن بدلاً من ذلك ، إذا قمنا بتغيير الحد ليكون 0.001،
that any experience is going to be labeled as positive.
فإن هذا يعني أن أي تجربة ستكون قيمتها إيجابية.
So, almost all of the data points are going to satisfy this condition.
لذا، فإن جميع نقاط البيانات تقريبًا ستفي بهذا الشرط.
So we're going to say that.
لذلك سنقول ذلك.
Everything is +1, and so this is going to be the optimistic classifier.
كل شيء هو 1+، وبالتالي سيكون هذا هو التصنيف المتفائل.
It's going to be say yeah, everything is +1, everything's good.
وسيكون الانطباع من وراء ذلك هو أن كل شيء +1، كل شيء جيد.
So by varying that threshold from 0.5 to something close to 0
إذاً بتغيير هذا الحد من 0.5 إلى شيء قريب من الصفر
to something close to 1, we're going to change between optimism and pessimism.
وإلى شيء قريب من 1، سنقوم بالتبديل بين التفاؤل والتشاؤم.
So if you go back to this picture of logistic regression, for example,
لذا إذا عدت إلى هذه الصورة التي تمثل الارتباط المنطقي، على سبيل المثال،
as a complete case.
كحالة كاملة.
We have this input, the score of x.
فسنجد هذا الإدخال وهو درجة x.
And the output here was the probability that y is equal to +1 given x and w.
والإخراج هنا هو احتمال y يساوي 1+ مع المعطيات x و w.
This should bring some memories maybe some sad, sad memories.
وهذا من شانه استحضار بعض الذكريات، التي قد تكون حزينة.
The threshold here is going to be a cut where we say,
وسوف يصبح الحد عبارة عن قطع حيث نعتبر
set y hat to be equal to +1 if it's greater than or equal to this threshold t.
ŷ تساوي +1 إذا كانت أكبر من هذا الحد الأدنى t أو تساويه.
So everything above the line will be +1 and
لذلك، سيكون كل شيء فوق السطر 1+
everything below the line will be labeled -1.
وكل شيء تحت السطر 1-.
Or concretely, let's see what happens if we set the threshold to be some very,
أو بشكل ملموس، دعنا نرَ ما سيحدث إذا قمنا بتعيين الحد
very high number.
ليكون عددًا كبيرًا جدًا.
So, t here is close to one.
قيمة t هنا قريبة جدًا من واحد.
So if t is some number close to one,
وإذا كان t عبارة عن رقم قريب من واحد،
then everything below that line will be labeled as -1.
إذن فقيمة كل شيء تحت هذا السطر ستكون -1.
And very, very few things there above the line here can be labeled as +1.
وتصبح أشياءً قليلة جدًا فوق السطر بقيمة 1+.
So, that's why we end up with a pessimistic classifier,
لذلك، فنحن نتعامل مع مصنف متشائم،
on the flip side if we set the t threshold to be something very,
ومن ناحية أخرى إذا قمنا بتعيين حد t ليصبح صغيرًا جدًا،
very small, so this is small t then everything's going to be above the line.
فإن كل شيء سيكون فوق السطر.
So everything's going to be labeled as +1, and
وبالتالي ستكون قيم كل شيء 1+.
very few data points are going to be labeled as -1.
وسيبقى القليل من الأشياء ذات القيمة 1-.
So we'll end up with the optimistic classifier.
وبالتالي نحن نتعامل مع مصنف متفائل.
So range in t from 0 to 1, takes us from optimism to pessimism.
إذاً، تراوح t بين 0 و 1، يبدل الأحوال من التفاؤل إلى التشاؤم.
In other words that spectrum that we said weren't navigate on can now be
وبعبارة أخرى، يمكن أن تكون المنطقة التي وعدنا باستكشافها
navigated for a single parameter, t, that goes between 0 and 1.
محددة في معلمة t المفردة التي تتراوح قيمتها من 0 إلى 1.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]